1800 Bryant Street Apt. 305 - San Francisco, CA 94110

 \square +1 (415) 335 6775 • \square andy@andygross.org • \square andygross.org • \square andygross **y** argv0 • ♠ argv0 • Conference Presentations: http://lanyrd.com/profile/argv0

Summary

I'm a veteran distributed systems, database, and cloud services expert with over 15 years experience building world class products, services, and engineering teams. I'm seeking technology and product leadership and founder opportunities at venture funded startups.

Experience

Opsee San Francisco, CA

Co-founder and CTO

2/2015-7/2015

Founded a developer-oriented monitoring company with friends. Brought investors into 1.5MM seed round, hired initial engineering team, and led implementation of the MVP product.

San Francisco, CA

Staff Software Engineer, Core Storage

3/2014-2/2015

Technical lead for Manhattan, Twitter's self-serve internal DBaaS.

- o Implemented a distributed rate limiter/admission control system based on PID control to prevent cluster overload.
- o Wrote an extensible integration testing tool to automate verification of cluster invariants and correctness checking.
- o Worked with other tech leads and management to establish unit testing, code style, and documentation guidelines and best practices.

Basho Technologies

San Francisco, CA

Chief Architect

12/2007-3/2014

Author of Riak, a leading NoSQL database and Basho's flagship product. I defined the technical and product direction as we grew the company from four to 140 employees in San Francisco, Cambridge, Herndon, London, and Tokyo.

- o Developed initial versions of all Basho Open Source and Enterprise software (Riak, RiakCS, Riak Enterprise Replication).
- o Participated in fundraising, closed licensing deals with Fortune 50 companies (Apple, Comcast, AT&T, Verizon, State Farm).
- o Presented at top industry conferences on distributed systems, guest lectured at Berkeley and Stanford on distributed systems in industry.

Mochi Media San Francisco, CA

Senior Systems Architect

5/2007-12/2007

Employee #3. Helped secure funding from Accel, rewrote MVP infrastructure (message queue, monitoring system, deployment/operational tools) to handle post-launch growth. Left to start Basho with Akamai colleagues.

Apple Cupertino, CA

Distributed Systems Engineer, Developer Tools

9/2005-5/2007

Hired to write a distributed compiler to speed builds for Apple's largest third party developers (Adobe, Microsoft).

- o Designed and implemented a distributed filesystem (see Patents and Publications).
- o Maintenance and feature development for the Xcode build system.
- o Presented work at WWDC 2006.

Akamai Technologies

Cambridge, MA

Senior Software Engineer

7/1999-9/2005

Employee #75. Hired to carry 21" CRT monitors for new hires, left as Senior Engineer leading design and development of custom high-margin products for the US Government.

- o Co-designed and implemented Akamai Content Storage, the backing store for the initial Apple iTunes Music Store launch.
- o Designed and implemented a reactive overly network that became the basis for the Akamai's highly profitable IP acceleration products.
- o Created an 'Internet Intelligence Portal', aggregating IDS, BGP, and performance data for consumption by the US Intelligence Community.

Patents and Publications

Bumgarner, William, Adam Swift, and Andrew Gross (2012). "MIRRORED FILE SYSTEM". US8286127 B2.

Gross, Andrew R. (2012). "The Architecture of Open Source Applications". In: vol. i. Chap. Riak and Erlang.

Education

Hacking, Learning,

Autodidact

Various

1977-Present

VIC-20, C64, Intel platforms **University of Connecticut**

Management, Finance,

Left to take pre-IPO position at Akamai

Storrs, CT 1996-1999